Rohini, Delhi, IN | LinkedIn | +91 885-148-1154 | LeetCode | tayalaastha360@gmail.com | GitHub

SDE | ORACLE | PYTHON | C++

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Skilled Software Development Engineer with expertise in Oracle, Python, C++, and SQL. Masters in Computer Applications & Data Analysis. Built AI applications and data visualizations, optimizing user experience through machine learning. Strong team player, fluent with full professional proficiency in English & Hindi.

✓ Oracle, PostgreSOL

KEY SKILLS

✓ Python

✓ C/C++	✓ Azure AWS GCP	✓ Snowflake	✓ Linux, Microsoft 365
EDUCATION			
Master of Computer Application Vivekananda Institute of Professional Studies TC, GGSIPU			2022 - 2024 Delhi
Post Graduate Diploma Degree in Data Analysis University School of Management Studies (Main Campus), GGSIPU			2021 - 2022 Delhi
Bachelor of Computer Applications Jagan Institute of Management Studies, GGSIPU			2018 - 2021 Delhi
Senior Secondary	2004 - 2018		

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Lancers Convent School

BluePi Consulting Pvt. Ltd. - Trainee Engineer

✓ Java

Mar 2024 – Sep 2024

Delhi

✓ Data Analysis

Pi Café (*June 2024 – August 2024*)

- Managed the PostgreSQL database and created data pipelines to transfer data between S3, PostgreSQL, and Snowflake.
- Led the design and implementation of Snowflake's raw, stage, and final layers, Power BI visualizations.
- Collaborated closely with the backend team on a POS system project and led the data team.

DTDC – Data Engineer Support (July 2024 – Present)

• Provide support for the DTDC project using GCP BigQuery, implement solutions using Python Kafka.

PROJECTS

Airline Fair Prediction MCA – 2023

Developed an AI-driven system in Python for optimizing airfare decisions, leveraging machine learning models like Random Forest and Ridge Regression. Deployed user-friendly website to help travelers identify cost-effective booking.

Song Recommendation Chatbot

MCA - 2023

Developed an AI-powered song recommendation chatbot in Python using PyCharm, analyzing user mood and preferences to provide personalized song suggestions, while incorporating Kivy for a cross-platform GUI interface.

Uber Ridership PGDDA – 2022

Utilized Python, Jupyter Notebook, and R Studio to analyze NYC Uber trip data from Kaggle, employing libraries like ggplot, ggthemes, and lubridate for comprehensive data visualization and analysis.

Make It Easy (Human Resource Management System)

BCA - 2021

Developed a Core Java HR management system with GUI in Java using NetBeans IDE, integrated with Microsoft .NET and XAMPP SQL Server for efficient record management.

CERTIFICATE AND AWARDS

Data Base Management System	Neptel -2024
Data Analytics Internship Plan	IBM SkillsBuild – 2024
AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals	Udemy – 2023
Introduction to Data Science in Python	Coursera – 2020
AI For Everyone	Coursera – 2020
Advance C++ Training	IIT Bombay – 2019